MUHAMMAD LUTHFI SUGARA NASUTION

Software Developer

+6282213451309

Sugaraluthfi@gmail.com

Medan, North Sumatera, Indonesia, 20228

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

i 12/2021 – Present

Global Investa Capital

♀ Indonesia

- Worked in the forex trading team to handle users who make trade, deposits and withdrawals.
- Developed and maintained NFT and Wallet services to claim profits.
- Designed and developed software applications base on user stories, requirements and design specifications.
- Developed RESTFul APi to control user functions using ExpressJS or NestJS with MongoDB as a persistence layer.
- Presented software development and lifecycle reports to CTO and CEO, receiving recognition for design ideas and implementation.
- Focused on front-end development, providing mentorship and coaching to 3 junior front-end developer using React and NextJS.

Software Developer

1 09/2020 - 11/2021

Bursaku.id

♀ Indonesia

- Developed Restful API to control user functions using ExpressJS with Mysql as a persistence layer while utilizing React on the frontend.
- Developed, tested, debugged, and documented software applications.
- Participated in code reviews with product team, and gained feedback from senior engineers and experience in writing custom and scalable code.
- Improved database performance by optimizing MySQL queries.
- Ensured all technical issues were ticketed.

Full Stack Developer

ii 04/2019 - 08/2020

Lunata Technologies

Indonesia

- Built and maintained existing applications using PHP, Laravel and MySql or PostgreSql.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams regarding product and design application.
- Translated wireframes/sketches into working prototypes to refine user interface behaviors.
- Analyzed and utilized application and programming documents to develop of clean, scalable and reusabled code.

SUMMARY

Software Developer with 6 years Structuring, Develop and Implementing interactive applications. I have focused on developing scalable and well-documented code. I enjoy working collaboratively but can also run with projects independently. Motivated to advance and expand my skill set through targeted mentorship and challenging projects.

LANGUAGES

English Professional

SKILLS

Git Javascript Typescript PHP ReactJS NextJS

VueJS Firebase React Native NodeJS ExpressJS

NestJS Laravel MongoDB MySQL PostgeSQL

Mongoose TypeORM Redux Vuex React Query

TailwindCss Bootstrap MUI ChakraUI Web3.js

Ethers.js Restful API Docker CI/CD Swagger

EDUCATIONS

Jest

Data Science & Al

University of North Sumatera

Computer Science

Mikroskil University

Degree

2014 - 2019

Bachelor's Degree

SOCIAL MEDIA



LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/luthfi-sugara/



Github

https://github.com/LuthfiSugara